Guide to German artists: miscellaneous correspondence, 1848-1927
Department of Special Collections
German artists: miscellaneous correspondence,
1848-1927
M0475
German artists, 1848-1947
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Miscellaneous correspondence between German artists.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, Stargardt auction items 536, 582, 584, 591, and 662, 1979.
Scope and Content
Arranged alphabetically by sender.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Begas, Carl, 1794-1854.; Bendemann, Edward Julius Friedrich, 1811-1889.; Bode, Wilhelm v., 1845-1929.; Bèurck, Heinrich, 1850-.; Camphausen, Wilhelm, 1818-1885.; Dettmann, Ludwig, 1865-1944.; Drechsler, Alexander, 1860-1897.; Ehrenberg, Carl, 1840-.; Engel, Otto Heinrich, 1866-1949.; Friese, Richard, 1854-.; Gebhardt, Edward von, 1838-1925.; Harburger, Edmund, 1846-1906.; Hofmann, Johann Michael Ferdinand Heinrich, 1824-1911.; Hèunton, Emil, 1827-1902.; Huybens.; Kalckreuth, Stanislaus, 1820-1894.; Kaulbach, Frieda Scotta.; Kaulbach, Friedrich August V., 1850-1920.; Kèorner, Ernst Karl Eugen, 1846-1927.; Kollwitz, Kèathe, 1867-1945.; Leistikow, Walter, 1865-1908.; Lenbach, Franz Seraph V., 1836-1904.; Liebermann, Max, 1847-1935.; Lindenschmit, Wilhelm Von, 1829-1895.; Lorenz, Richard, 1858-1915.; Max, Gabriel Cornelius V., 1840-1915.; Menzel, Adolf Von, 1815-1905.; Meysenheim, Emilie.; Mèuller-Kurzwelly, Konrad Alexander, 1855-1914.; Orlik, Emil, 1870-1932.; Pietsch, Ludwig, 1824-1911.; Quandt, Johann Gottlob V., 1787-1859.; Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917.; Souchan, Wilhelm Ferdinand, 1825-1876.; Trèubner, Alice, 1875-1916.; Valentiner, Wilhelm Reinhold, 1880-1958.; Velde, Henry van de, 1863-1957.; Verlat, Charles, 1824-1890.; Whistler, James Abbott McNeill, 1834-1903.; Art, German.; Art, Modern--19th century.; Art, Modern--20th century.
Collection Contents
- Begas, Carl (1794-1854): ALS, 1p., 1854 June 10To "Werthgeschätzter Herr." (Box 1, Folder 1)
  (S-662)
- Bendemann, Edward Julius Friedrich (1811-89). ALS, 1p., 1848 June 10To Miss C. Jacobi. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  (S-584)
- Bode, Wilhelm v. (1845-1929).ALS, 2pp., Nov. 8, 1918To Straßmann. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  (S-536)
- Bürck, Heinrich (b.1850) ALS, 3pp., June 9, 1881To "Sehr geehrter Herr." (Box 1, Folder 4)
  (S-591)
- Camphausen, Wilhelm (1818-85). ANS, Oct. 1862. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Dettmann, Ludwig (1865-1944).ALS, 2pp., April 14, 1913To Royal Academy of Arts, Berlin. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Drechsler, Alexander (1860-97).ACS, May 4, 1884To H. Wallach. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ehrenberg, Carl (b.1840) ACS, 1p., Aug. 1884To H. Wallach. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Engel, Otto Heinrich (1866-1949) ALS, 1p., May 25, 1913To "Sehr verehrter Herr Präsident." (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Friese, Richard (b.1854) ALS, 2pp., March 1, 1911To "Euer Hochwohlgeboren." (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Gebhardt, Edvard von (1838-1925). ALS, 2pp., Nov. 28, 1910To President [of the Royal Academy of Arts, Berlin]. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Harburger, Edmund (1846-1906) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ALS, 1p., Nov. 12, 1896To Kunz Meyer.
  - ACS, May 13, 1905To the Gentlemen of the Jury.
- Hofmann, Johann Michael Ferdinand Heinrich (1824-1911). ALS, 1p., May 21, 1907To Strudel. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Hünton, Emil (1827-1902). ADS, 1p., n.d., To Carl Becker. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Huybens. ALS, 2pp., n.d., To Baron de Rumohr. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Kalckreuth, Stanislaus (1820-1894) ALS, 4pp., July 24, 1868To "Mein lieber Baron." (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Kaulbach, Frieda Scotta Letter, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Kaulbach, Friedrich August von. (1850-1920) Letters, 1910-1918, 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Körner, Ernst Karl Eugen (1846-1927) ALS, 4pp., Nov. 2, 1895To "Verehrter Herr Direktor." (Box 1, Folder 19)
  (KB-1978)
- Kollwitz, Käthe (1867-1945) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ACS, Jan. 26, 1925 To Sabine Lepsius.
  - TLS, 1p., July 23, 1927To Strassmann
- Leistikow, Walter (1865-1908). (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - ALS, 2pp., Nov. 26, 1903To [P.] Strassmann.
  - ALS, 3pp., Sept. 22, 1904To Leopold Kalckreuz
- Lenbach, Franz Seraph von. (1836-1904) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ALS, 1p., Jan. 4, 1896To Lillian Sanderson.
  - ALS, 1p., June 31, 1896To ["Theuerer freund"]
  - ALS, 3pp. June 30, 1900To [Hans] Petersen.
  - ALS, 1p., n.d. To "Verehrtester Herr College".
- Liebermann, Max (1847-1935) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ALS, 1p., Feb. 20, 1899To Felix Bondi.
    (S-582)
  - ALS, 2pp., March 26, 190[1]To Reinhold Lepsius.
    (S-659)
  - ALS, 3pp., Aug. 27, 1908To Felix Bondi.
  - ALS, 1p., Dec. 25, 1909To "Sehr geehrter Herr."
  - ALS, 1p., Feb. 4, 1925To "Sehr verehrter Herr Prof."
  - AC, n.d. To Felix Bondi.
- Lindenschmit, Wilhelm von. (1829-1895) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ACS, n.d. To [Ludwig von] Löfftz.
  - ALS, n.d. To "Lieber Freund."
- Lorenz, Richard (1858-1915). A, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Max, Gabriel Cornelius von. (1840-1915) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - ALS, 2pp., March 3, 1895To E. Haeckel.
  - ACS, Aug. 28, 1900To Heinemann family.
- Menzel, Adolf von. (1815-1905) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - ANS, n.d. To Theodore Mommsen.
- Menzel, Adolf von. (1815-1905) (Box 1, Folder 27a)
  - ANS, Dec. 8, 1876Note on one of two leaves from L'Art Revue hebdomadaire illustrée, 1875.
- [Meysenheim, Emilie]. ALS, 3pp., Feb. 2, 18[9]6To "Sehr geehrten Herr Baron." (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Müller-Kurzwelly, Konrad Alexander (1855-1914). ACS, Aug. 30, 1900To David Heinemann (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Orlik, Emil (1870-1932) ALS, 1p., n.dTo Haeckel. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Pietsch, Ludwig (1824-1911) ACS, June 17, 1900To Kitty Haufstaengl. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Quandt, Johann Gottlob von. (1787-1859) ALS, 2pp., Aug. 1, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Rodin, Auguste (1840-1917) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - ALS, 3pp., Jan. 2, 1904To "Monsieur le Secrètaire Honoraire".
  - AC, n.d. To "Chère Madame."
- Souchan, Wilhelm Ferdinand (1825-1876) ALS, 2pp., April 27, 1872To "Intendant" ad "Baron". AMs.S, 3pp. Enclosed with above letter. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Trübner, Alice (1875-1916) ALS, 2pp., Dec. 16, 1905To Theodor Pixis. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Valentiner, Wilhelm Reinhold (1880-1958) ALS, 2pp., April 11, 1909To Reisinger. (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Velde, Henry van de (1863-1957) TLS, 1p., June 25, 1909To Sauter. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Verlat, Charles (1824-90) LS [mimeo], 1p., Oct. 25, 1879To Baron v. Loan. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Whistler, James Abbott McNeill (1843-1903) ADS, 1p., Feb. 12, 1898To Vereinigung bildender Künstler Oesterreichs. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Unidentified senders. AL[S], 4pp., Aug. 24, 1908To Max Liebermann. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Autographs. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Jury of the VIII. International Art Exhibit in Munich. 28 signatures on reverse of menu for dinner in honor of the jury, July 20, 1901
  - Society for German Art Abroad. 21 signatures on reverse of membership application, Feb. 15, 1909
  - [Walinzsky]. Watercolor illustrated autograph, Sept. 5, 1893